<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="info_uv_index">
        <item>UV index</item>
        <item>
The ultraviolet index is an international standard measurement of the strength
of the sunburn-producing ultraviolet (UV) radiation.\n\n

* UVR is involved in tanning, accelerated skin ageing, ocular damage, and the development of skin cancer.\n\n
* UVR also has beneficial effects due to the production of vitamin D in the skin and its immune-modulating effects on inflammatory skin diseases.\n\n
* UVR is often confused with infrared radiation. The temperature, however, does not affect UV radiation levels. UV radiation can be just as high on a cool or even cold day as it is on a hot one, especially if skies are clear.\n\n

UVR is categorised according to wavelength, which ranges from 100–400 nm:\n\n

* Ultraviolet A (UV-A) = 320–400nm\n\n
* Ultraviolet B (UV-B) = 290–320nm\n\n
* Ultraviolet C (UV-C) = 100–290nm\n\n

UV-C radiation is filtered out or absorbed in the outer atmosphere so does not pose a problem to humans. UV-A and UV-B radiation are the primary causes of sunburn.\n\n

###### Who is at risk of sunburn?\n\n

Skin phototyping categorises people into one of six groups based on baseline skin colour and the tendency to tan and burn when exposed to UV radiation.\n\n

Other factors that increase the incidence of sunburn include:\n\n

* Regions situated closer to the equator\n\n
* Areas at high altitude – UV radiation increases 4% for every 300m increase in elevation\n\n
* Skin exposure between 10 am, and 2 pm – 65% of UV radiation reaches the earth between these times\n\n
* Clear skies: clouds and environmental pollution reduce UV radiation\n\n
* Environmental reflection – UV radiation is 80% reflected by snow and ice\n\n

            Public health organizations recommend that people protect themselves (for example, by applying sunscreen to the skin and wearing a hat and sunglasses) if they spend substantial time outdoors when the UV index is 3 or higher\n\n

            ###### Details \n\n

The UV index is a number linearly related to the intensity of sunburn-producing UV radiation at a given point on the Earth\'s surface.\n\n

For example, if a light-skinned individual (without sunscreen) begins to sunburn in 30 minutes at UV index 6, then that individual should expect to sunburn in about 15 minutes at UV index 12 – twice the UV, twice as fast.\n\n

The erythemally weighted downwelling UV fluxes are determined using the Tropospheric Ultraviolet Radiation Model (TUV). The fluxes is altered by the effects of:\n\n


* sun-earth distance\n\n
* solar zenith angle\n\n
* total ozone amount\n\n
* tropospheric aerosol optical depth\n\n
* elevation\n\n
* snow/ice reflectivity\n\n
* cloud transmission\n\n


        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>